Contact

3057938246 (Mobile) andygp25@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ andygonzalezmba (LinkedIn) plus.google.com (Personal) andygonzalezmba.blogspot.com (Blog)

Top Skills

IT Management Leadership SharePoint

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt (ICBB)

Programming in C#

CIW Web Development Professional MCP

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

Andy Gonzalez

Manager of Solutions Architecture / Engineering

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Summary

IT operations leader, program management, enterprise architecture, technology evaluation and selection, IT organization transformation and outsourcing, application development, enterprise application migration / implementations, analytics/BI, HIT, Healthcare/Insurance. Expert improving Collaboration, Communication, Process Reengineering, boosting Productivity and delivering Enterprise Solutions.

Recently Certified:

==========

- * ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management
- * Certified Scrum Master (CSM)
- * IASSC Certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt (ICBB)

Experience

PayerFusion Holdings LLC
Manager of Solutions Architecture / Engineering
June 2018 - Present

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

- *Manage all areas of IT (Project Management, Software Development, Infrastructures (Cloud/ On Premise), Business Applications (CMS, CRM, SharePoint), Systems Engineering, Network Engineering, Telecom, Information Security, IT Governance and Help Desk)
- *Overseeing technical projects in alignment with organizational goals.
- *Directing the effective delivery of networks, development, and disaster recovery systems and processes.
- *Working with engineers to find solutions to manage business activities.
- *Supervising a team of workers, while working closely with management, external vendors and advisers.
- *Preparing yearly budgets and presenting proposals for capital projects to senior management.
- *Leading efforts to improve IT processes.

- *Identify security vulnerabilities and eliminate them with strategic solutions that increase data safety.
- *Direct and support implementation of software and hardware upgrades.
- *Identify and recommend new technology solutions that we can implement in our department.
- *Defined IT Policies and Procedures.
- *Defined Change Management process and committee.
- *Defined and Manage Cloud (Azure) and On-Premise Infrastructures.
- *Responsible for attracting and retaining top talented employees.
- *Manage company websites based on WordPress (registrar, hosts and SSL certificates)
- *Manage and prioritize projects/requests using PMI (PMP) and Scrum methodologies.
- *Manage SDLC.
- *Manage Development, Testing and Production environments.
- *Manage development and infrastructure team

Managed Systems/Services/Technologies:

- -Azure
- -Office 365 (SharePoint, Dynamics 365, Flows, OneNote, Power BI,

PowerApps, OneDrive, Teams, Exchange, Yammer, Skype...)

- -Servers (AD, DHCP, DNS, Web, FTP, SMTP, Reports, Files, SQL)
- -Network (Routers, Switches, Firewall)
- -RingCentral (Telecom)
- -CMS
- -CRM
- -Jira
- -Microsoft Project
- -Visual Studio
- -Team Foundation Server
- -Power BI/SSRS
- -SolarWinds
- -Telerik (Kendo UI)

Leon Medical Centers Solutions Architect / SharePoint Administrator March 2016 - June 2018 (2 years 4 months) Doral

^{*} Defined/Implemented a new Physical/Logical/Information Architecture.

- * Provide input to business relationship management teams regarding improvement goals for business divisions or functions that can be achieved with Enterprise solutions.
- * Identify opportunities for technology improvements, improved organizational efficiency and effectiveness, and innovative solutions to help achieve business benefits through SharePoint development.
- * Proactively work to reduce costs and improve productivity (continuous improvement)
- * Ensure the team is diligent in creating thorough solution documentation that can be used as input into future development tasks and training.
- * Motivate team members to work collaboratively and effectively.
- * Responsible for building the framework and features of the portal.
- * Responsible for Capacity Planning and Topology.
- * Defined new intranet Governance and Establish Best Practices.
- * Defined the Disaster Recovery Strategy.
- * Linked and configured OWA and PWA servers to the Production Farm.
- * Created Global Navigation using Manage Metadata Service App.
- * Migrated content from Shared Drive to SharePoint Site Collections. Shared Drive will be completely eliminated.
- * Responsible for Vendors collaboration and Vendors management.
- * Responsible for managing the intranet that will be he main business app for the users to do their daily computer related jobs.
- * Configured and used Metalogix and AvePoint solutions for the Production and Development Farms.
- * Build forms using Infopath 2013 and SharePoint Designer 2013.
- * Mentor and Train other technical and no technical resources.
- * Setup Office 365 / SharePoint Online Services, Security and Information Architecture.

Systems Integration:

- * Footprints (Ticketing System)
- * Tableau and SSRS(Reports)
- * Project Server 2013
- * Office Web Apps Server 2013
- * Citrix Apps (Storefront)
- * Yammer (Enterprise)
- * Office 365
- * Google Analytics
- * Epic

Independent Living Systems, LLC
SharePoint Administrator / Developer
December 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 4 months)
Doral, FL

- Responsible for the SharePoint/SQL architecture design, planning, implementation, testing, and maintenance.
- SharePoint development.
- Manage Metadata
- IT Project Manager
- SQL Programming
- Migrated SharePoint Content and Configuration Databases to new clustered SQL server.
- SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).
- SDLC
- Enterprise Software Architecture
- Deployed Microsoft BI solutions on the SharePoint/SQL Server stack and applications via Visual Studio.
- Demonstrated ability to work well with clients and provide technical direction in a multidisciplinary team environment.
- Makes recommendations regarding changes to current standards as appropriate and keeps abreast of new technology developments.
- Available on call 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.
- Security, configuration, maintenance, and expansion of the Enterprise SharePoint Sites and SharePoint based applications.
- Coordination with business teams and IT teams (Active Directory,
 Development, DBAs, and Security) to support implemented SharePoint architecture that utilizes best practices and meets Enterprise objectives.
- * Web Applications Development
- Deployment of SharePoint functionality and assisting users in utilizing SharePoint (Rollout, Training, transitioning responsibilities to other teams).

Miami-Dade County
Systems Analyst / Programmer
November 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 2 months)
Miami International Airport

- IT Project Manager
- Expert in SQL development/Programming and Integration to SharePoint using BCS.

- SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).
- SDLC
- Expert with SharePoint 2010 / 2013 development and administration including ASP.net / C# and web parts for custom development.
- Manage Metadata
- Available on call 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.
- Makes recommendations regarding changes to current standards as appropriate and keeps abreast of new technology developments.
- Ensure the success of the team's duties, reporting and BI initiatives.
- Ensure the development of quality documentation for all critical Project
- Coordinate with technical team during technical architecture design reviews, development and implementation of critical Project
- Project management as required
- Security, configuration, maintenance, and expansion of the Enterprise SharePoint Sites and SharePoint based applications. Strong focus on Web/ SharePoint Solutions and SharePoint Administration enabling rapid solution implementation lifecycle.
- Maintaining information architecture and ongoing administration of all Site collections, Monitoring, Integration, Data Feeds, deployment of solution packages
- Maintaining and enforcing enterprise portal governance and best practices for rapid solution development.
- * Web Applications Development
- Performs other related duties as assigned

Mundo Stores Inc Director of Engineering (Consultant) January 2009 - March 2014 (5 years 3 months) Miami, Florida

- •As Director of Engineering, I was able to attract, hire and manage a highly technical team responsible for the migration to client/server technologies, development of corporate internet/intranet sites, system integration and real-time electronic data interfaces corporate internet/intranet sites, system integration, real-time electronic data interfaces
- •Designed and Implemented Software/Infrastructure Architecture.
- •Responsible for Processes Improvement. Used ITIL standards
- •Responsible for the CRM System
- •Developed and designed external and internal sites (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ASP.NET, C#)
- •Responsible for the Engineering and Project Management teams.

- Integrated and Maintained SQL Databases.
- •Assists management in planning, resource allocation, Project estimation, and scheduling for various Projects and initiatives
- •Provides support and guidance to the Project teams in performing their assignments, tasks, and monitoring the successful delivery (execution)
- •Oversee the development of business requirements documents that meet customer's business needs.
- •Security, configuration, maintenance, and expansion of the Enterprise SharePoint Sites and SharePoint/Web based applications. Strong focus on Web/SharePoint Solutions and SharePoint Administration enabling rapid solution implementation lifecycle.
- •Coordination with business teams and IT teams (Active Directory, Development, DBAs, and Security) to support implemented SharePoint architecture that utilizes best practices and meets Enterprise objectives.
- •Maintained and enforced enterprise portal governance and best practices for rapid solution development.

Education

Western Governors University

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Information

Technology · (2013 - 2016)

Western Governors University

Bachelor of Science Information Technology - Software, Web Applications Development \cdot (2012 - 2013)

New Horizons

20461 - Querying Microsoft SQL Server · (2014 - 2014)

New Horizons

10175 - Microsoft SharePoint 2010, Application Development · (2014 - 2014)